how do you go about creating a course
and then actually making money with it
you might be looking for a plan of what
to do so that you're not wasting time
and actually get the results that you
want today we're going to be going over
exactly what to do if you want to make
money with online courses my name is
jeremi Kowski and for the last 21 years
I've been working in the space of
courses years ago we did DVDs and CD
products as well as live seminars and in
that I've created an entire career
around helping people market sell and
create the world's best courses that
have generated tens of millions of
dollars for myself and my clients in the
process and so I want to break this down
for you strategically so you know step
by step you don't have to guess as to
what to do to get results to create your
own course here's one of the first
things that I find is that a lot of
people um think about creating courses
in the wrong way number one I have to
get this out of the way as far as this
goes creating a course is not going to
make you
money don't lose hope by that because
that's just one piece of the equation
you have to learn how to get people to
buy your course and that's exactly what
I help people with in my client growth
accelerator program listen if you are
somebody who wants to work with me to
help you build a course and get the
results that you want want in your
business I can help you with that you
can join the waiting list for my program
you can click the link in the
description below and I can work with
you on this but here's the thing is
that people pay for value and so you
have to find something that is valuable
for people to deliver to them in your
course now you might be saying well I
don't know what I could deliver with a
value we got one of two different types
of people either they they they have way
too many ideas or they have no ideas at
all if you have no ideas at
all what I would look at is what do you
have experience in knowledge about
things that you can help people with
that you've done over the last 15 years
that other people might be interested in
now most people that I mean actually
have more ideas than possible okay and
so what I encourage people to do is this
is I take a little bit more of an
intuitive approach and Instinct and an
instinctive approach as far as this goes
combined with using artificial
intelligence to help you decide what
topic to create a course on so if you're
deciding on picking your Niche that's
one of the first stages as far as that
goes finding what topic to create a
course around so figure out couple of
different ideas couple of different
people that you want to serve what
problems you solve and you're going to
actually teach people that as far as
that goes and it goes beyond just
teaching but it's actually being
captivating and somebody that leads
people
to take action this is an art and a
skill that I Mentor people on inside of
my coaching program is how to actually
create these world class courses but
when it comes to actually putting it
together you might be saying well
there's so many different platforms out
there there's lots of different things
to do I'm not sure where to start and
your head can spin because there's all
these different unknowns that you're
thinking about I want you to keep it
very simple everybody that I work with
when it comes to creating courses I
always say start with the simple stuff
pick a couple cple of ideas that you
want to help people with let's say you
want to help men get fit who are also
dealing with confidence issues and you
want them to grow spiritually okay and
you're not sure should I start a
spiritual course should I make a fitness
course or should I do something around
confidence I say combine all three
together and help men who want to grow
spiritually in their confidence as well
as their Fitness so they can become the
most powerful version of themselves and
here's the other thing to look at is to
expand your vision when it comes to
creating a course I want you to
think two to three courses in the future
temporarily about what this could build
upon okay so like I have a client right
now she's creating a course all about
toilet training children but I told her
listen you could literally go into
creating curriculum for parents you
could create different Milestone stages
of lessons for parents that go beyond
just toilet training and because they
trusted you in that area
as well she has experience as a as a
monory instructor that she could
literally take her experience over over
I think it's like 20 years of experience
in that area and turn it into a
business that is not just toilet
training but it goes beyond that into
these other areas that's what I think
about with people as far as that goes
you know when I got my start in my
business I was the the the Facebook ads
guy and we it building guy okay and
years ago I was just the video editing
guy I was all everybody was all about
video editing now we find we don't even
really do a lot with video editing if
you can record the content if you can
learn to speak well if you can learn to
be articulate if you can learn to
Captivate people with your language that
goes a lot further than editing content
down okay but when it comes to
creating courses you can take your
experience and then have a vision for
where you're going as to who you're
going to serve so think about a problem
that you can
solve uh you know there's a lady that
followed me for a while she was like I I
help uh people in Probate Court uh not
have to deal with these issues well
check this out there are stages now of
that that you can go into after this
helping people with uh grief counseling
um as well as what to do with investing
if there's certain finances involved as
far as that goes and so keeping things
in just one small tiny little box when
it comes to creating your course this
one little it idea really is a
small-minded way of thinking so we want
to expand our thinking to think further
than that because what's actually going
to build a business is creating
something that people can come into your
ecosystem and work with you on for
instance I don't just help people create
courses I take the whole process of
going from idea I want to create a
course to making 10 of millions of
dollars in a sustainable real business
and all of the challenges and pitfalls
people run into in business so they can
have Financial Freedom so they have the
right messaging so they know how to
communicate how to sell how to Market
and all of those different aspects and
that's exactly what we go over in my
accelerator program and we've helped
hundreds of clients in that program as
well as I've coached thousands of people
over the years on these topics is how to
take their information their knowledge
as well as how to
brainstorm ideas that they might not
have already to take things a step
further now I want to show you something
real quick with artificial intelligence
here's some great things that you can do
I want to take our example that we were
talking about a little bit earlier about
the guy who wants to create something
for fitness and we're going to go into
chat GPT right here and and you can
actually log in with chat GPT and you
can use this we can go type this in
right here very easily
if you have an account you can actually
use chat gbt 40 as
well so let me let me actually pull up
this screen right here and we're going
to pull up this chat jpt window right
here with chat jpt
40 okay if you create a free account you
can actually use this uh yourself as far
as that goes let me bring my camera back
up here so you can actually see me right
here all right so let's type this in
let's say you got these ideas I want to
create a program for men who want
spiritual growth health and
fitness and confidence put these
together and generate 20 possible sub
niches for this to create a course okay
and I know I misspelled things but I
want to show you the AI you don't need
to get it perfect with the spelling it
will actually fill in the gaps as far as
that goes and it knows what you mean
which is really cool okay so this gives
you ideas as far as what you could
do with those different ideas if you use
Ai and just type in the different ideas
that you have it can help you optimize
this as well let's say that you're stuck
you're not knowing where to start you
can do this I want to create a course
but I don't know where to start ask me a
series of questions to find the best
idea based on my experience and look at
this the AI can now start asking asking
you about your background your
professional experience certain skills
topics you're into who do you want to
help different format and if you don't
have answers to some of the questions
that's okay as well here's another one
that I like can you
brainstorm 100 possible topics for
courses I could sell online niches that
I could make a course in and so you
could take any of these potential topics
or Nicha
and expand them out
further with different ideas let's just
take one of these right here playing
guitar for beginners
okay brainstorm 20
possible sub niches for playing guitar
for beginners okay and look there's all
these different ideas that the AI starts
to generate so when it comes to
brainstorming and ideas we have no lack
of ability to come up with ideas because
we have access to these tools now at our
disposal which is amazing and prior to
having these different tools it might
have been a struggle to be able to know
okay what topic should I use what should
I talk about what should I create a
course
around now there's no excuse as far as
that goes if you're stuck you're
wondering what should I do go into the
AI and start playing around with that
now one once you pick an idea where do
you go from there okay here's what I
recommend people do is I recommend that
you do a test market and you do and you
adopt what's called an
experimentation mindset and do an alpha
release strategy okay so the alpha
release strategy is this is that you're
willing to put something out there to
test it out with a group of people
doesn't have to be perfect to see how
people respond to gain feedback to
optimize it later you know we've been
for so long that we have to have
everything figured out and be this
perfect expert before we put stuff out
there in courses and I can I tell you
this that's completely wrong it's
completely bogus it's completely not
healthy way of thinking it's based on uh
what's taught to us inside of Academia
and it's not legitimate when it comes to
building a business because everybody
that I've ever met has value that they
can deliver a course on and they can get
better and improve over time by learning
list listen you don't need impostor
syndrome you don't need to worry about
doing it all perfect take action start
taking action start putting things out
there and start connecting with people
now one of the best ways to test out a
course idea is you could create content
say through a YouTube channel or through
your social media and see what people
respond to but what I love is then you
can also start to grow an email list and
you can start to have people show up to
live trainings that you might host let's
say you're doing a live event I'm going
to host a live event on Saturday uh you
know July 20th where we're going to walk
you through XYZ topic about
freestyling uh blues guitar and you want
to and and and then the idea is you're
able to build an audience around you of
people that want that thing and you're
able to connect with these people and
start to develop how you're going to be
teaching this so a lot of people make
the mistake of they they create a course
in the beginning they they they develop
a course they record it they create all
these lessons lesson plan uh worksheets
all this that's not the right approach
to take and when I work with my clients
I told them don't take this approach
instead gather a tribe of people around
you connect with people validate your
idea before you invest a lot of time
into it and then start pre-selling
something that you can deliver over time
to people now again there's risk
involved with this but it's a great risk
because it actually puts some fire under
you to take action
to do something that you committed to
and I see this more often than not I
meet thousands of people all the time
when they say I want to create a
course and they struggle they struggle
struggle struggle because they are so
caught up in the weeds of all the
logistics of what to
do and I meet
them year down the road two years down
the road five years down the road and
they haven't made any progress this is
more often than not when people start
with the logistic side of things that I
happens and so what I encourage people
to do is like take a step back let go of
needing it all to be perfect and let's
just start have fun with the process
let's start by you know putting a few
things out there to connect with some
people and then build from there record
some content package it into something
that you could sell as a course and
Reach people with now what are you going
to use to actually sell it well we use a
platform that I love it's called think
if.com and there's a few other platforms
that you can check out but I really
enjoy thinkific dcom because they
provide us with a learning system that
allows me to engage with people it
allows me to to to to share my content
and and for the courses that we have for
our clients that we have inside of my
client growth accelerator we have
actually developed it out where we have
a number of different courses from where
to start start here beginner courses
intermediate the learning library as
well as weekly
calls here's a course we just finished
finished all about creating a world
class
course we have lessons here that you can
go through
checklists recording gear using AI to
plan out your lessons all of that and
those are things that I love to help
people with inside of our courses that
we have right
here using a platform like think ific
streamlines a lot of the technology side
of it because you can focus on just
recording the content get out of your
head get out of your your own way stop
overthinking it don't need it to be
perfect and start connecting with the
right people that you're looking to
reach now once you have the course now
it comes time to Market it and that's
where we want to actually put together
what's called an irresistible offer
something that people are going to buy
into something that connects deeply to
the soul of what their desires are and
if you're somebody that wants to work
with me to create your irresistible
offer to develop your course to start to
reach the clients you want I'd love to
work with you in my client growth
accelerator program that's exactly what
we work with people on every single week
and to start getting you the results
that you're looking for okay you don't
need
to reinvent the wheel do thousands of
complex things spend all these hours on
it it's about taking one step forward
and for many of you right now you might
be caught up in your head overthinking
the process one of the things that I
will encourage you with and this is kind
of what I'm going to leave on this note
right here is leaving perfectionism at
the door because you will never actually
create a perfect course trust me I've
tried and failed because then I end up
not creating a course and so what I like
to do is actually put some pressure on
myself I have to record it by this date
create an artificial constraint or a
deadline of I got to get it done in the
next two weeks and then get something
out there and that's something that I
put put a fire on to coach my clients
with to help them actually get results
is they got to take action quickly and
they got to get stuff going fast so they
can start to reach the clients that they
want to reach listen if you are somebody
that is just starting out and you want
to create a course I'd love to help you
with that stay plugged into my YouTube
channel subscribe watch some of the
different videos that we have as well
join my accelerator program and let's
start working together to get you the
results that you want so I can work with
you personally
to help you to come alongside you to
build out your marketing with you so you
can start making the kind of money that
you want to make all right listen I'll
see you on our next video we'll talk
soon have a good one